

Pasadena and Irvine, CAjayesswang.com

in @jayesswang

SUMMARY

A creative storyteller, visual strategist, and empathetic advocate of user-centered experiences that align with the business goals.

A perceptive, adaptable, and tech savvy ENTP-A (Myers-Briggs) leveraging a 20-yr international work history in multiple industries and roles. Able to analyze and solve a problem from multiple angles with a global perspective.

DESIGN PROCESS

interviews
focus groups
surveys
competitive analysis
user research
card sorting
info architecture
flow diagrams
sketches
wireframes
rapid prototyping
usability testing
heuristic evaluation

TOOLS

figma sketch invision adobe cc usabilityhub usertesting html / css / javascript git / github g-suite

LANGUAGE

mandarin chinese

RECENT PROJECTS

WHAT DO YOU MEME?TM MOBILE GAME

Convert a popular tabletop game for adults into a mobile game. Tools include Google Forms, Figma, UsabilityHub, Google Forms, Loom, YouTube.

JW PORTFOLIO

Hand code a responsive portfolio website from scratch and host it on GitHub Pages. Tools include Google Forms, Figma, UsabilityHub, Loom, YouTube.

BOXLY

Design an SaaS that allows users to collect, store, and share info all from one place. Tools include Google Forms, Draw.io, Balsamiq, Sketch, InVision, UserTesting.

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

UX DESIGN APPRENTICE | BLOC.IO

2018

• Train in an 8-mth apprenticeship under an experienced UX professional.

PHOTOGRAPHER & DIGITAL TECH | JW PHOTOGRAPHY

2008 - 2018

• Notable clients include: Bebe, Halston, Nordstrom, HauteLook, Ozsale.

GLOBAL CREATIVE PHOTOGRAPHER | FOREVER 21

2013 - 2017

- Shoot products for Global Creative, E-commerce, and The Branded Shop.
- Collaborate across departments; demonstrate corporate diplomacy.
- **Second-in-command** to photography supervisor; **train** new photographers; some duties exceed original job title and description.

WEB PRODUCER | KAC MEDIA

2010 - 2011

- Produce content, research the story, write scripts, conduct interviews, create video outlines/rough draft in Final Cut Pro.
- Start-up work culture with small, nimble, and fluid teams. Wear multiple hats, assisting as needed in all tasks from pre- to post-production.

SENIOR EDITOR | ENVISION MBA (Taipei, Taiwan)

2006 - 2010

- Asia's #1 education consultancy helping MBA applicants tailor their branding
 & strategy when applying to the top 50 MBA programs worldwide.
- Guide prospective MBA applicants through the application process; lead essay-writing workshops and conduct mock interviews.
- Hundreds of **students successfully placed at**: INSEAD, HEC Paris, London Business School, Wharton, Sloan, Columbia, Oxford, Haas, and others.

EDUCATION

BLOC.IO | UX DESIGN APPRENTICESHIP

2018

Certificate in UX Design

LOS ANGELES CENTER OF PHOTOGRAPHY

2012

Certificate in Commercial Photography

UNIVERSITY OF SOUTHERN CALIFORNIA (USC)

2006

• B.A. in English & Creative Writing / Minor in Music Business